Command station, this is ST-321.
Code clearance blue.
We're starting our approach.
Deactivate the security shield.
The security deflector shield
will be deactivated...
when we have confirmation
of your code transmission.
Stand by.
You are clear to proceed.
We're starting our approach.
Inform the commander
that Lord Vader's shuttle has arrived.
Sir.
Lord Vader, this is an unexpected
pleasure. We're honoured.
You may dispense
with the pleasantries, Commander.
I'm here to put you back on schedule.
I assure you, Lord Vader,
my men are working as fast as they can.
Perhaps I can find
new ways to motivate them.
I tell you this station
will be operational as planned.
The emperor does not share your
optimistic appraisal of the situation.
But he asks the impossible.
I need more men.
Then perhaps you can tell him
when he arrives.
- The emperor's coming here?
- That is correct, Commander...
and he is most displeased with
your apparent lack of progress.
We shall double our efforts.
I hope so, Commander, for your sake.
The emperor is not
as forgiving as I am.
Of course I'm worried.
And you should be too.
Lando Calrissian and poor Chewbacca
never returned from this awful place.
Don't be so sure.
If I told you half the things
I've heard about this Jabba the Hutt...
you'd probably short-circuit.
R2, are you sure
this is the right place?
I'd better knock, I suppose.
There doesn't seem to be anyone here.
Let's go back and tell Master Luke.
Goodness gracious me!
I don't think
they're going to let us in, R2.
We'd better go.
R2, wait.
Oh, dear. R2.
R2, I really don't think
we should rush into all this.
Oh, R2!
R2, wait for me!
Just you deliver Master Luke's message
and get us out of here.
Oh, my!
Oh, no.
Oh, my.
We bring a message
to your master,Jabba the Hutt.
And a gift.
What gift?
He says that our instructions
are to give it only to Jabba himself.
I'm terribly sorry. I'm afraid he's ever
so stubborn about these sort of things.
R2, I have a bad feeling about this.
Good morning.
The message, R2.
The message.
Greetings, Exalted One.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Luke Skywalker,
Jedi knight and friend to Captain Solo.
I know that you are powerful,
mighty Jabba...
and that your anger with Solo
must be equally powerful.
I seek an audience with Your Greatness
to bargain for Solo's life.
With your wisdom, I'm sure
we can work out an arrangement...
which will be mutually beneficial...
and enable us to avoid
any unpleasant confrontation.
As a token of my goodwill,
I present to you a gift-
these two droids.
What did he say?
Both are hard-working
and will serve you well.
This can't be.
R2, you're playing the wrong message.
He's no Jedi.
There will be no bargain.
We're doomed.
I will not give up
my favourite decoration.
I like Captain Solo where he is.
R2, look. Captain Solo.
And he's still frozen in carbonite.
What could possibly
have come over Master Luke?
Was it something I did? He never
expressed any unhappiness with my work.
How horrid!
Good. New acquisitions.
You are a protocol droid,
are you not?
I am C-3PO-
Yes or no will do.
Well, yes.
How many languages do you speak?
I am fluent in over six million forms
of communication and can readily-
Splendid. We have been
without an interpreter...
since our master got angry
with our last protocol droid...
and disintegrated him.
Disintegrated?
Guard, this protocol droid
might be useful.
Fit him with a restraining bolt...
and take him back up to
His Excellency's main audience chamber.
R2, don't leave me!
You're a feisty little one...
but you'll soon learn some respect.
I have need for you on
the master's sail barge...
and I think you'll fill in nicely.
Ah! Do that again!
I have come for the bounty
on this Wookiee.
Oh, no. Chewbacca.
At last we have the mighty Chewbacca.
Yes, I am here,
Your Worshipfulness.
Yes?
The illustrious Jabba
bids you welcome...
and will gladly pay you
the reward of 25,000.
I want 50,000. No less.
"50,000. No less. "
What did I say?
The mighty Jabba asks why
he must pay 50,000.
Because he's holding
a thermal detonator.
This bounty hunter
is my kind of scum...
fearless and inventive.
Jabba offers the sum of 35...
and I do suggest you take it.
He agrees!
Just relax for a moment.
You're free of the carbonite.
You have hibernation sickness.
- I can't see.
- Your eyesight will return in time.
- Where am I?
- Jabba's palace.
Who are you?
- Someone who loves you.
- Leia.
I gotta get you out of here.
What's that?
I know that laugh.
Hey,Jabba.
Look,Jabba, I was just
on my way to pay you back.
I got a little sidetracked.
It's not my fault.
It's too late for that, Solo.
You may have been a good smuggler...
but now you're Bantha fodder.
Look-
Take him away.
Jabba, I'll pay you triple.
You're throwing away a fortune here.
Don't be a fool.
Bring her to me.
We have powerful friends.
You're gonna regret this.
I'm sure.
I can't bear to watch.
Chewie?
Chewie, is that you?
Wait a minute.
I can't see, pal.
What's going on?
Luke? Luke's crazy.
He can't even take care of himself,
much less rescue anybody.
AJedi knight?
I'm out of it for a little while,
everybody gets delusions of grandeur.
I'm all right, pal.
I'm all right.
I must speak with Jabba.
No bargain.
You will take me to Jabba now.
You serve your master well.
And you will be rewarded.
At last! Master Luke's
come to rescue me.
Master.
Luke Skywalker,Jedi knight.
I told you not to admit him.
I must be allowed to speak.
He must be allowed to speak.
You weak-minded fool!
He's using an old Jedi mind trick.
You will bring Captain Solo
and the Wookiee to me.
Your mind powers
will not work on me, boy.
Nevertheless...
I'm taking Captain Solo
and his friends.
You can either profit by this
or be destroyed.
It's your choice, but I warn you
not to underestimate my powers.
Master Luke, you're standing on-
There will be no bargain, young Jedi.
I shall enjoy watching you die.
Oh, no! The rancor!
Bring me Solo and the Wookiee.
They will all suffer for this outrage.
Han.
- Are you all right?
- Fine. Together again, huh?
- Wouldn't miss it.
- How are we doin'?
- Same as always.
- That bad, huh?
- Where's Leia?
- I'm here.
Oh, dear.
His High Exaltedness,
the great Jabba the Hutt...
has decreed that you are
to be terminated immediately.
Good. I hate long waits.
You will therefore be taken
to the Dune Sea...
and cast into the Pit of Carkoon...
nesting place
of the all-powerful Sarlacc.
Doesn't sound so bad.
In his belly, you will find a new
definition of pain and suffering...
as you are slowly digested
over 1,000 years.
On second thought,
let's pass on that.
You should have bargained,Jabba.
That's the last mistake
you'll ever make.
I think my eyes are getting better.
Instead of a big dark blur,
I see a big light blur.
There's nothing to see.
I used to live here, you know.
You're gonna die here,
you know. Convenient.
Just stick close to Chewie and Lando.
I've taken care of everything.
Great.
Soon you will learn to appreciate me.
I'm terribly sorry.
R2, what are you doing here?
I can see you're serving drinks,
but this place is dangerous.
They're going to execute Master Luke,
and if we're not careful, us too.
I wish I had your confidence.
Victims of the almighty Sarlacc...
His Excellency hopes
that you will die honourably.
But should any of you
wish to beg for mercy...
the great Jabba the Hutt
will now listen to your pleas.
3PO, you tell that slimy piece
of worm-ridden filth...
he'll get no such pleasure from us!
Right?
This is your last chance.
Free us or die.
Move him into position.
Put him in.
Easy, Chewie.
Help!
Chewie, you're hit?
Where is it?
Han, Chewie!
Lando.
Boba Fett?
Boba Fett? Where?
- Lando, grab it!
- Lower it!
I'm trying!
Grab me, Chewie.
Grab it!
Grab it. Almost.
You almost got it.
Gently, now.
Easy. Hold me, Chewie.
Chewie, give me the gun.
- Don't move, Lando.
- Wait! I thought you were blind!
I can see a lot better.
Don't move.
A little higher!
Chewie, pull us up.
Up, Chewie. Up.
We gotta get out of here.
Not my eyes! R2, help!
Quickly, R2!
Beast!
Get the gun!
Point it at the deck.
Point it at the deck!
R2, where are we going?
I couldn't possibly-
Come on.
- Let's go. Don't forget the droids.
- We're on our way.
I'll meet you back at the fleet.
Hurry. The Alliance
should be assembled by now.
- I will.
- Luke, thanks.
Thanks for coming after me.
Now I owe you one.
That's right, R2.
We're going to the Dagobah system.
I have a promise to keep...
to an old friend.
Rise, my friend.
The Death Star will be
completed on schedule.
You've done well, Lord Vader.
Now I sense you wish to continue
your search for young Skywalker.
Yes, my master.
Patience, my friend.
In time, he will seek you out.
When he does,
you must bring him before me.
He has grown strong.
Only together can we turn him
to the dark side of the Force.
As you wish.
Everything is proceeding
as I have foreseen.
That face you make-
Look I so old to young eyes?
No, of course not.
I do.
Yes, I do.
Sick have I become.
Old and weak.
When 900 years old you reach...
look as good you will not.
Soon will I rest.
Yes. Forever sleep.
Earned it I have.
Master Yoda, you can't die.
Strong am I with the Force...
but not that strong.
Twilight is upon me,
and soon night must fall.
That is the way of things...
the way of the Force.
But I need your help.
I've come back
to complete the training.
No more training do you require.
Already know you
that which you need.
Then I am a Jedi.
Not yet.
One thing remains-
Vader. You must confront Vader.
Then- only then-
a Jedi will you be.
And confront him you will.
Master Yoda...
is Darth Vader my father?
Rest I need.
Yes.
Rest.
Yoda, I must know.
Your father he is.
Told you, did he?
Yes.
Unexpected this is.
And unfortunate.
Unfortunate that I know the truth?
No.
Unfortunate that
you rushed to face him...
that incomplete
was your training...
that not ready
for the burden were you.
I'm sorry.
Remember, a Jedi's strength
flows from the Force.
But beware.
Anger, fear, aggression...
the dark side are they.
Once you start down the dark path...
forever will it dominate your destiny.
Do not-
Do not underestimate
the powers of the emperor...
or suffer your father's fate you will.
When gone am I...
the last of the Jedi will you be.
The Force runs strong in your family.
Pass on what you have learned.
There is...
another...
Skywalker.
I can't do it, R2.
I can't go on alone.
Yoda will always be with you.
Obi-Wan.
Why didn't you tell me?
You told me Vader betrayed
and murdered my father.
Your father was seduced
by the dark side of the Force.
He ceased to be Anakin Skywalker
and became Darth Vader.
When that happened...
the good man who was
your father was destroyed.
So what I told you was true...
from a certain point of view.
A certain point of view?
Luke, you're going to find
that many of the truths we cling to...
depend greatly
on our own point of view.
Anakin was a good friend.
When I first knew him...
your father was already a great pilot...
but I was amazed how strongly
the Force was with him.
I took it upon myself
to train him as a Jedi.
I thought that I could instruct him
just as well as Yoda.
I was wrong.
There is still good in him.
He's more machine now than man...
twisted and evil.
I can't do it, Ben.
You cannot escape your destiny.
You must face Darth Vader again.
I can't kill my own father.
Then the emperor has already won.
You were our only hope.
Yoda spoke of another.
The other he spoke of
is your twin sister.
But I have no sister.
To protect you both
from the emperor...
you were hidden from your father
when you were born.
The emperor knew, as I did...
if Anakin were to have any offspring...
they would be a threat to him.
That is the reason why your sister
remains safely anonymous.
- Leia is my sister.
- Your insight serves you well.
Bury your feelings deep down, Luke.
They do you credit...
but they could be made
to serve the emperor.
Look at you. A general, huh?
Someone must have told them about
my manoeuvre at the Battle of Tanaab.
Don't look at me, pal.
I just said you were a fair pilot.
I didn't know they were looking for
somebody to lead this crazy attack.
I'm surprised they didn't
ask you to do it.
Who says they didn't?
But I ain't crazy.
You're the respectable one, remember?
The emperor's made a critical error
and the time for our attack has come.
The data brought to us by the Bothan
spies pinpoint the exact location...
of the emperor's new battle station.
We also know
that the weapon systems...
of this Death Star
are not yet operational.
With the imperial fleet
spread throughout the galaxy...
in a vain effort to engage us...
it is relatively unprotected.
But most important of all...
we've learned that
the emperor himself...
is personally overseeing
the final stages...
of the construction
of this Death Star.
Many Bothans died
to bring us this information.
Admiral Ackbar, please.
You can see here the Death Star
orbiting the forest moon of Endor.
Although the weapon systems on this
Death Star are not yet operational...
the Death Star does have
a strong defence mechanism.
It is protected by an energy shield...
which is generated
from the nearby forest moon of Endor.
The shield must be deactivated
if any attack is to be attempted.
Once the shield is down,
our cruisers will create a perimeter...
while the fighters
fly into the superstructure...
and attempt to knock out
the main reactor.
General Calrissian has volunteered
to lead the fighter attack.
Good luck.
You're gonna need it.
General Madine.
We have stolen a small imperial shuttle.
Disguised as a cargo ship
and using a secret imperial code...
a strike team will land on the moon
and deactivate the shield generator.
Sounds dangerous.
Wonder who they found
to pull that off.
General Solo,
is your strike team assembled?
My team's ready. I don't have
a command crew for the shuttle.
It's gonna be rough.
I didn't wanna speak for you.
- That's one.
- General, count me in.
I'm with you too.
- What is it?
- Ask me again sometime.
Hi, Han, Chewie.
"Exciting" is hardly the word
I would choose.
Look, I want you to take her.
I mean it. Take her.
You need all the help you can get.
She's the fastest ship in the fleet.
All right, old buddy.
I know what she means to you.
I'll take good care of her.
She won't get a scratch.
All right?
Right.
I got your promise.
Not a scratch.
Would you get going, you pirate?
Good luck.
You too.
- Got her warmed?
- Yeah, she's coming up.
I don't think the Empire had Wookiees
in mind when they designed her, Chewie.
Hey, you awake?
Yeah. I just got a funny feeling,
like I'm not gonna see her again.
Come on, General. Let's move.
Right. Chewie, let's see
what this piece of junk can do.
- Ready, everybody?
- All set.
Here we go again.
All right, hang on.
What is thy bidding, my master?
Send the fleet
to the far side of Endor.
There it will stay until called for.
What of the reports of the rebel fleet
massing near Sullust?
It is of no concern.
Soon the rebellion will be crushed
and young Skywalker will be one of us.
Your work here is finished, my friend.
Go out to the command ship
and await my orders.
Yes, my master.
If they don't go for this, we're gonna
have to get out pretty quick.
We have you on our screen now.
Please identify.
Shuttle Tydirium requesting
deactivation of the deflector shield.
Shuttle Tydirium, transmit
the clearance code for shield passage.
Transmission commencing.
Now we find out if that code
is worth the price we paid.
It'll work. It'll work.
Vader's on that ship.
Don't get jittery, Luke.
There are a lot of command ships.
Keep your distance, Chewie, but don't
look like you're keeping your distance.
I don't know. Fly casual.
Where is that shuttle going?
Shuttle Tydirium,
what is your cargo and destination?
Parts and technical crew
for the forest moon.
Do they have a code clearance?
It's an older code, sir,
but it checks out.
I was about to clear them.
I'm endangering the mission.
I shouldn't have come.
It's your imagination, kid.
Come on. Let's keep
a little optimism here.
Shall I hold them?
No. Leave them to me.
I will deal with them myself.
As you wish, my lord. Carry on.
They're not going for it, Chewie.
Shuttle Tydirium...
deactivation of the shield
will commence immediately.
Follow your present course.
Okay. I told you
it was gonna work.
No problem.
I told you it was dangerous here.
- Should we try and go around?
- It'll take time.
This whole party will be
for nothing if they see us.
Chewie and I will take care of this.
You stay here.
Quietly. There might be
more of them out there.
Hey...
it's me.
Go for help! Go!
Great. Come on!
Over there! Two more of them.
I see them. Wait. Leia!
Hey, wait!
Quick, jam their comlink.
Centre switch.
Move closer.
Get alongside that one.
Keep on that one.
I'll take these two.
General Solo, somebody's coming.
Where's Leia?
- She didn't come back?
- I thought she was with you.
We got separated.
We better go look for her.
Take the squad ahead. We'll meet
at the shield generator at 0300.
Come on, R2.
We'll need your scanners.
Don't worry, Master Luke.
We know what to do.
And you said it was pretty here.
Cut it out.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Well, looks like I'm stuck here.
Trouble is, I don't know where here is.
Maybe you can help me.
Come on. Sit down.
I promise I won't hurt you.
Now come here.
All right.
You want something to eat?
That's right.
Come on.
Look. It's a hat.
It's not gonna hurt you. Look.
You're a jittery little thing,
aren't you?
What is it?
Freeze!
Come on. Get up.
- Get your ride. Take her back to base.
- Yes, sir.
What the-
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
I told you to remain
on the command ship.
A small rebel force has penetrated
the shield and landed on Endor.
Yes, I know.
My son is with them.
- Are you sure?
- I have felt him, my master.
Strange that I have not.
I wonder if your feelings
on this matter are clear, Lord Vader.
They are clear, my master.
Then you must go to
the sanctuary moon and wait for him.
He will come to me?
I have foreseen it.
His compassion for you
will be his undoing.
He will come to you,
and then you will bring him before me.
As you wish.
Master Luke.
There's two more
wrecked speeders back there.
And I found this.
I'm afraid that R2's sensors
can find no trace of Princess Leia.
I hope she's all right.
What, Chewie?
I don't get it.
It's just a dead animal.
Chewie, wait! Don't!
Nice work.
Great, Chewie.
Great. Always thinking
with your stomach.
Take it easy. Let's just figure
a way to get out of this thing.
Han, can you reach my lightsabre?
Yeah. Sure.
R2, I'm not sure
that's such a good idea.
It's a very long drop!
Hey. Point that thing
someplace else.
Hey!
Han, don't. It'll be all right.
Chewie, give them your crossbow.
Oh, my head.
Oh, my goodness.
Do you understand
anything they're saying?
Oh, yes, Master Luke.
Remember that I am fluent
in over six million forms-
What are you telling them?
"Hello," I think.
I could be mistaken-
they're using a very primitive dialect-
but I do believe they think
I am some sort of god.
Why don't you use your divine
influence and get us out of this?
I beg your pardon, General Solo,
but that just wouldn't be proper.
Proper?
It's against my programming
to impersonate a deity.
Why, you-
My mistake.
He's an old friend of mine.
Hey.
I have a really bad feeling about this.
What did he say?
I'm rather embarrassed,
General Solo...
but it appears you are to be the main
course at a banquet in my honour.
Your Royal Highness.
These are my friends.
3PO, tell them
they must be set free.
Somehow I got the feeling
that didn't help us very much.
3PO, tell them
if they don't do as you wish...
you'll become angry
and use your magic.
But, Master Luke, what magic?
I couldn't possibly-
Tell them.
You see, Master Luke?
They didn't believe me...
just as I said they wouldn't.
Wait.
What's happening?
Put me down!
Help!
Somebody!
Somebody help!
Master Luke! R2, quickly!
Thank goodness.
Thanks, 3PO.
I never knew I had it in me.
...Tatooine...
Princess Leia... R2.
...Darth Vader!
...Death Star.
...Jedi... Obi-Wan Kenobi.
Yes, R2, I was just coming to that.
Master Luke...
...Millennium Falcon... Cloud City.
...Vader!
Han Solo...
...carbon.
...Sarlacc.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
Wonderful. We are now
a part of the tribe.
Just what I always wanted.
Short help's better than
no help at all, Chewie.
The scouts will show us the quickest
way to the shield generator.
Good. How far is it?
Ask him.
We need some fresh supplies too.
Try and get our weapons back.
Hurry up.
I haven't got all day.
Luke, what's wrong?
Leia, do you remember
your mother-
your real mother?
Just a little bit.
She died when I was very young.
What do you remember?
Just images really. Feelings.
Tell me.
She was... very beautiful.
Kind... but sad.
Why are you asking me this?
I have no memory of my mother.
I never knew her.
Luke, tell me.
What's troubling you?
Vader is here.
Now. On this moon.
How do you know?
I felt his presence.
He's come for me.
He can feel when I'm near.
That's why I have to go.
As long as I stay, I'm endangering
the group and our mission here.
- I have to face him.
- Why?
He's my father.
Your father?
There's more. It won't be easy
for you to hear it, but you must.
If I don't make it back,
you're the only hope for the Alliance.
Don't talk that way.
You have a power I don't understand
and could never have.
You're wrong, Leia.
You have that power too.
In time, you'll learn
to use it as I have.
The Force is strong in my family.
My father has it.
I have it.
And...
my sister has it.
Yes. It's you, Leia.
I know.
Somehow...
I've always known.
Then you know
why I have to face him.
Luke, run away.
Far away.
If he can feel your presence,
then leave this place.
- I wish I could go with you.
- No, you don't.
You've always been strong.
But why must you confront him?
Because there is good in him.
I've felt it.
He won't turn me over
to the emperor.
I can save him. I can turn him
back to the good side.
I have to try.
Hey, what's going on?
Nothing. I just wanna
be alone for a little while.
Nothing?
Tell me.
What's going on?
I can't tell you.
Could you tell Luke?
Is that who you could tell?
I'm sorry.
Hold me.
This is the rebel that surrendered.
Although he denies it,
I believe there may be more of them...
and I request permission
to conduct a further search of the area.
He was armed only with this.
Good work, Commander.
Leave us.
Conduct your search
and bring his companions to me.
Yes, my lord.
The emperor has been expecting you.
I know, Father.
So, you have accepted the truth.
I've accepted the truth that you were
once Anakin Skywalker, my father.
That name no longer
has any meaning for me.
It is the name of your true self.
You've only forgotten.
I know there is good in you.
The emperor hasn't
driven it from you fully.
That was why
you couldn't destroy me.
That's why you won't bring me
to your emperor now.
I see you have constructed
a new lightsabre.
Your skills are complete.
Indeed you are powerful,
as the emperor has foreseen.
Come with me.
Obi-Wan once thought as you do.
You don't know the power
of the dark side.
I must obey my master.
I will not turn,
and you'll be forced to kill me.
If that is your destiny.
Search your feelings, Father.
You can't do this.
I feel the conflict within you.
Let go of your hate.
It is too late for me, son.
The emperor will show you
the true nature of the Force.
He is your master now.
Then my father is truly dead.
The main entrance
to the control bunker...
is on the far side
of that landing platform.
- This isn't gonna be easy.
- Don't worry.
Chewie and me got into a lot of places
more heavily guarded than this.
What's he saying?
He says there's a secret entrance
on the other side of the ridge.
Admiral, we're in position.
All fighters accounted for.
Proceed with the countdown.
All groups assume attack coordinates.
Don't worry.
My friend's down there.
He'll have that shield down on time.
Or this'll be
the shortest offensive of all time.
All craft, prepare to jump
into hyperspace on my mark.
All right. Stand by.
Back door, huh? Good idea.
It's only a few guards.
This shouldn't be too much trouble.
It only takes one to sound the alarm.
Then we'll do it real quiet-like.
- Oh, my. Princess Leia.
- Quiet.
I'm afraid our furry companion...
has gone and done something
rather rash.
There goes our surprise attack.
Look, over there! Stop him!
Not bad for a little furball.
There's only one left.
You stay here.
We'll take care of this.
I have decided that we shall stay here.
Hey!
Welcome, young Skywalker.
I have been expecting you.
You'll no longer need those.
Guards, leave us.
I'm looking forward
to completing your training.
In time, you will call me master.
You're gravely mistaken.
You won't convert me
as you did my father.
Oh, no, my young Jedi.
You will find that
it is you who are mistaken...
about a great many things.
His lightsabre.
Ah, yes. AJedi's weapon.
Much like your father's.
By now you must know your father
can never be turned from the dark side.
So will it be with you.
You're wrong.
Soon I'll be dead-
and you with me.
Perhaps you refer to
the imminent attack of your rebel fleet.
Yes.
I assure you we are quite safe
from your friends here.
Your overconfidence
is your weakness.
Your faith in your friends is yours.
It is pointless to resist, my son.
Everything that has transpired
has done so according to my design.
Your friends up there
on the sanctuary moon...
are walking into a trap,
as is your rebel fleet.
It was I who allowed the Alliance...
to know the location
of the shield generator.
It is quite safe
from your pitiful little band.
An entire legion
of my best troops awaits them.
I'm afraid the deflector shield...
will be quite operational
when your friends arrive.
All right!
Up! Move!
Quickly. Quickly.
Han, hurry.
The fleet will be here any moment.
Charges. Come on. Come on!
Oh, my. They'll be captured.
Wait! Come back!
R2, stay with me.
Freeze!
You rebel scum.
- All wings report in.
- Red Leader standing by.
- Grey Leader standing by.
- Green Leader standing by.
Lock S-foils in attack positions.
May the Force be with us.
We've gotta be able to get
a reading on that shield- up or down.
How could they be jamming us
if they don't know-
if we're coming.
Break off the attack.
The shield is still up.
I get no reading. You sure?
Pull up! All craft pull up!
Take evasive action. Green Group,
stick close to Holding Sector MV-7.
Admiral, we have
enemy ships in Sector 47.
It's a trap.
Fighters coming in.
There's too many.
Accelerate to attack speed.
Draw their fire away from the cruisers.
Copy, Gold Leader.
Come, boy.
See for yourself.
From here, you will witness
the final destruction of the Alliance...
and the end
of your insignificant rebellion.
You want this...
don't you?
The hate is swelling in you now.
Take your Jedi weapon.
Use it.
I am unarmed.
Strike me down with it.
Give in to your anger.
With each passing moment
you make yourself more my servant.
It is unavoidable.
It is your destiny.
You, like your father...
are now...
mine.
All right, move it.
Hello. I say, over there.
Were you looking for me?
Bring those two down here.
They're on their way.
R2, are you sure this was a good idea?
Freeze.
Don't move.
We surrender.
The code's changed.
- We need R2.
- Here's the terminal.
R2, where are you?
We need you at the bunker
right away.
Going? What do you mean?
Going where, R2?
Wait. R2, this is
no time for heroics.
Come back!
Watch yourself, Wedge.
Three from above.
- Red Three, Red Two, pull in.
- Got it.
Three of them coming in, 20 degrees.
Cut left.
I'll take the leader.
They're heading
for the medical frigate.
Pressure's steady.
Only the fighters are attacking.
What are the Stardestroyers waiting for?
We're in attack position, sir.
- Hold here.
- We're not going to attack?
My orders are from the emperor himself.
He has something special planned.
We only need to
keep them from escaping.
As you can see,
my young apprentice...
your friends have failed.
Now witness the firepower...
of this fully armed
and operational battle station.
Fire at will, Commander.
Fire.
That blast came from the Death Star.
That thing's operational.
Home 1, this is Gold Leader.
We saw it.
All craft prepare to retreat.
You won't get
another chance at this, Admiral.
We have no choice, General Calrissian.
Our cruisers can't repel
firepower of that magnitude.
Han will have that shield down.
We've gotta give him more time.
We're coming.
Come on.
R2, hurry!
My goodness!
Why did you have to be so brave?
Well, I suppose I could
hot-wire this thing.
I'll cover you.
Yes, I said closer.
Move as close as you can...
and engage those Stardestroyers
at point-blank range.
At that close range, we won't last long
against those Stardestroyers.
We'll last longer than we will
against that Death Star...
and we might
take a few of them with us.
She's gonna blow!
I'm hit!
Your fleet is lost...
and your friends on the Endor moon
will not survive.
There is no escape...
my young apprentice.
The Alliance will die...
as will your friends.
Good.
I can feel your anger.
I am defenceless.
Take your weapon.
Strike me down
with all of your hatred...
and your journey towards
the dark side will be complete.
- Look!
- Get him off of there.
I think I got it.
I got it!
Are you all right?
- Let's see.
- It's not bad.
- Freeze!
- Oh, dear.
Don't move.
- I love you.
- I know.
Hands up.
Stand up.
Stay back.
Get down here.
She's wounded.
No, wait.
I got an idea.
Good.
Use your aggressive feelings, boy.
Let the hate flow through you.
Obi-Wan has taught you well.
I will not fight you, Father.
You are unwise
to lower your defences.
Your thoughts betray you, Father.
I feel the good in you, the conflict.
There is no conflict.
You couldn't bring yourself
to kill me before...
and I don't believe
you'll destroy me now.
You underestimate
the power of the dark side.
If you will not fight...
then you will meet your destiny.
Good.
- Watch out. Squad at.06.
- I'm on it, Gold Leader.
Good shot, Red Two.
We're sure in the middle of it now.
Come on, Han, old buddy.
Don't let me down.
It's over, Commander.
The rebels have been routed.
They're fleeing.
We need reinforcements
to continue the pursuit.
Send three squads to help.
- Open the back door.
- Sir.
Throw me another charge.
You cannot hide forever, Luke.
I will not fight you.
Give yourself to the dark side.
It is the only way
you can save your friends.
Yes.
Your thoughts betray you.
Your feelings for them are strong...
especially for...
sister.
So you have a twin sister.
Your feelings have now
betrayed her too.
Obi-Wan was wise
to hide her from me.
Now his failure is complete.
If you will not turn
to the dark side...
then perhaps she will.
Never!
Good!
Your hate has made you powerful.
Now, fulfil your destiny...
and take your father's place at my side.
Never.
I'll never turn to the dark side.
You've failed, Your Highness.
I am a Jedi...
like my father before me.
So be it,Jedi.
Move! Move!
The shield is down. Commence attack
on the Death Star's main reactor.
We're on our way. Red Group,
Gold Group, all fighters follow me.
I told you they'd do it.
If you will not be turned...
you will be destroyed.
Young fool.
Only now, at the end...
do you understand.
Your feeble skills are no match
for the power of the dark side.
You have paid the price
for your lack of vision.
Father, please!
Now, young Skywalker...
you will die.
I'm going in.
Here goes nothing.
Lock onto the strongest power source.
It should be the power generator.
Form up. Stay alert.
We could run out of space real fast.
Split up and head back to the surface.
See if you can get a few
of those TIE fighters to follow you.
Copy, Gold Leader.
That was too close.
We've got to give
those fighters more time.
Concentrate all fire
on that Super Stardestroyer.
Sir, we've lost our
bridge deflector shields.
Intensify the forward batteries.
I don't want anything to get through.
Intensify forward firepower!
Too late!
Help me take this mask off.
But you'll die.
Nothing can stop that now.
Just for once...
let me...
look on you with my own eyes.
Now go, my son.
Leave me.
No. You're coming with me.
I'll not leave you here.
I've got to save you.
You already have, Luke.
You were right.
You were right about me.
Tell your sister...
you were right.
Father.
I won't leave you.
There it is.
Wedge, go for the power regulator
on the north tower.
Copy, Gold Leader.
I'm already on my way out.
Move the fleet
away from the Death Star.
They did it!
I'm sure Luke wasn't
on that thing when it blew.
He wasn't.
I can feel it.
You love him.
Don't you?
Yes.
All right. I understand.
Fine.
When he comes back...
I won't get in the way.
It's not like that at all.
He's my brother.
Wesa free!